Okay, what up y'all? We're back with a
brand new video. Make sure you like and
subscribe if you appreciate the content.
Make sure you sub on school. I have a
lot of stuff coming up over there. Uh
today we're going to be installing LM
Studio so you can run your own LLM
locally on your computer.
Um
you'll be able to do a lot of agentic
stuff uh
and use stuff like open claw AI agents
and all that stuff using this LM Studio
program. Um I might go over a llama CPP
too if there's any um ask for it, but
today we're only going to do the LM
Studio simple setup.
Uh and it's pretty easy, nothing too
crazy. So, I'll just jump into it right
now. Uh you can just type LM Studio
like this.
Uh and you can just grab the first link.
Uh maybe not the first link, but the
download link. And you'll go over here
to download LM Studio. Uh you grab that.
Whether you're on Linux, Mac OS, or
Windows, you'll be able to run it. It
should work.
Uh I already have it installed, but
let's just do it for uh the sake of the
video here.
It's uh
almost done.
600 megabytes. So, just wait for that
and uh I'll open it up when it's done.
Okay. So, you open it up. You open up
the downloader, the installer. Okay.
Uh you do I agree, install it. Um
just choose whatever uh
hard drive you want to put it on. And
you install it.
The [__] was that?
Yeah, at the end and you coming back?
What the [__] bro?
That is [__] up. Anyways,
once you're done, you can just finish
and run LM Studio. Um have it checked.
It's going to open up the program. And
there it is. So, this is LM Studio. Uh
obviously I already have stuff over
there. Let's just clear that. Um, and
you are in. So, this is LM Studio. With
this program, you'll be able to download
uh, models directly from Hugging Face on
your PC and uh, you'll be able to load
them uh, through uh, this platform um,
directly instead of, you know, doing
complicated stuff. You don't need to do
that. You can just use this. Uh, so, how
do you get models, right? So, that's the
easy part.
You just click here and you just select
the model you want. Um, most models are
going to be there by default and it will
show you what you can uh, load directly
on your PC. Um, I have uh,
5090, so I can run, you know, a Q6 uh,
quantization.
For those who don't know what a
quantization is, um,
if you've been using image generation
models, it's basically the FP8 int8. Um,
it's basically lower um,
precision uh, on the model, but it makes
the model smaller and easier to run on,
you know, whatever hardware you have.
Um, so, if you have 24 gigs of VRAM, you
can try uh, a Q4 here.
Um, there are other versions of this
specific model. So, if you type "quant
uh, 3.8",
you'll get, you know, all those
different variants um, and you can just
choose uh, GGUF over there.
And if you go
down, oh, it's not showing you for this.
Okay, if you select this one, for
example, you'll have all the
quantizations
all the way down to Q1, which is a
one-bit version of the model. Um, I
personally would not go into a Q3. Uh,
if you're going to do that, you're going
to be getting really bad results
usually. Um, Q3, Q4, and up is probably
where you want to be. But, obviously,
that's going to depend on your um
your hardware, right? And the the only
thing that really matters is your VRAM
in this case.
Um, there are other ways to run it
without um
having, you know, a lot of VRAM, but
that's not what we're going to cover
today.
So, yeah, that's pretty much it. So,
once you have your model downloaded, I
already have it over here.
I have multiple versions, too. Um
what you can do is just go in uh the tab
developer. You can do control two.
And with that, you'll be able to load
the model directly on your PC or server.
Um, personally, I run it on my other
server other PC. Uh, so it's just going
to load the model. Um, for the settings,
uh you'll have default settings. Uh, I
have my own setup over here, but mo- for
most people, it's going to be um
you know, empty.
Uh, so, just leave basic settings, and
uh you'll be good.
So, you should not even be seeing this.
This is what you'll be seeing, right?
Um, you can turn up the context context
if you want. Um, not really necessary if
you're only doing, you know, comfy UI
prompting and stuff like that. If you
want to do like heavy-duty stuff like
coding and all that [__] uh you'll
you'll have to turn up the context all
the way up, obviously.
Um, but if you're only doing like, you
know, small stuff, leave it at that or
default, and load the model.
Okay?
Okay, we are ready to go. So, if we go
in the chat here, we can just select the
model and we can start chatting with it.
If we just say test.
So, now it's thinking. I'm not I'm not
sure why you're thinking that much for
just a test, bro, but whatever. Uh
that's one of the issues with uh Qwen
3.8, but you can turn off the thinking
over here.
And if we just do another test, it
should be instant.
Yeah, there we go. So, uh from there we
can do, you know, a lot of stuff. We can
plug that model directly inside Hermes
agent or Open Claw or uh all these other
um
you know, RNAs, uh Deep Seek RNA as
well. Should work absolutely fine. I did
test it and does work pretty well.
Um so, that's pretty much it for that um
that part in installation and then
downloading the model. It's really
simple. Um if you want to plug the model
uh inside something else, right? This is
what you're going to need. Uh reachable
at that's your local uh IP for uh the
server running um
LM Studio.
And you can just plug that wherever you
need it and you should be able to be you
should be able to contact the model
through uh that uh URL. Um if you have
other uh settings you you can play
around with. So, if you want to uh
stream the server over your local
network, you can just check that.
Um and it's going to basically make the
model available on your other PC, your
laptop, whatever.
Uh so, yeah, that's pretty cool. Uh the
server on local network.
And yeah, from there you can do a lot of
stuff. Uh next video I'm going to
install Hermes agent directly and then
plug uh Quinn 20.8
in it and then we're going to install
Sage attention
using all the AI agents. You're not
going to have to do anything. It's going
to install everything for you and it's
going to be super nice.
So that's pretty much it. Make sure you
like and subscribe if you appreciate the
content. I'll see you in the next one.
Peace.